Previously on the show.
Episode sebelumnya.
Wolffy got into the factory by pretending to help with cannon making.
Wolffy masuk pabrik dengan pura-pura bantu buat meriam.
The goats busted Wolffy's plot just in time,
Para Kambing merusak rencana Wolffy tepat waktu,
turning the explosion into a birthday salute for Hope.
mengubah ledakan jadi pesta ulang tahun untuk Hope.
But the problem with transporting the cannon remains unsolved.
Tapi masalah pengangkutan meriam belum terpecahkan.
Can they find a more reliable way of transportation?
Bisakah mereka mencari cara transportasi yang lebih andal?
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: Spread Your Wings and Fly High."
Petualangan Langit Pulau Terbang: Lebarkan Sayapmu dan Terbang Tinggi.
I can deliver the weather fruits alone.
Aku bisa antar buah cuaca sendiri. Paddi, kau kembali saja ke pabrik.
Okay, have a safe trip.
Baik, hati-hati di jalan.
All the weather fruits are almost delivered.
Semua buah cuaca hampir terkirim.
Are you all right?
Kau tak apa-apa?
Why are there still so many weather fruits left?
Kenapa masih banyak buah cuaca tersisa?
Weslie and some of the staff went to deliver it.
Weslie dan beberapa staf mengirimnya,
But we are still understaffed.
tapi masih kurang orang.
If we don't deliver it in time, the land will be gravely affected.
Jika tak segera dikirim, akan berpengaruh pada tanah.
What should we do then?
Lalu, harus bagaimana?
How about we use the remote control wings I invented?
Bagaimana jika pakai sayap kendali jarak jauh ciptaanku?
The remote control wings...
- Alat jarak jauh... - Yang rusak...
Three houses...
- Tiga rumah... - Dan dua gedung?
No... it's too dangerous.
Tidak, terlalu berbahaya.
-But... -Speak no more.
- Tapi... - Sudah cukup.
We should get back to work.
Kita harus kembali bekerja.
Paddi.
Paddi.
They're just exaggerating.
Mereka berlebihan. Apa sayap kendali jarak jauhmu menakutkan?
You know as well as I that my inventions always fail.
Kau sendiri pun tahu bahwa penemuanku selalu gagal.
It's withered again. What should we do?
Layu lagi. Kita harus bagaimana?
Let me use my latest invention, a growth agent, to help you.
Pakai penemuanku yang terbaru, perangsang pertumbuhan.
Director's invention is awesome.
Penemuan Direktur itu luar biasa.
-Help! -What's going on?
- Tolong! - Ada apa?
This is a portable weather fruit cleaner I invented.
Ini pembersih buah cuaca portabel buatanku.
Isn't it awesome?
Hebat, 'kan?
They are right to worry.
Wajar jika mereka khawatir.
But didn't your remote control wings save my life before?
Bukankah sayap kendali jarak jauhmu menyelamatkanku?
The ones I used to save you were second generation wings.
Itu sayap generasi kedua.
We have improved it and made the third generation wings.
Sudah diperbaiki dan buat sayap generasi ketiga.
But the manager won't let me test them.
Tapi manajer melarangku mengujinya.
We can test them by delivering the weather fruits, can't we?
Kita bisa uji dengan mengantar buah cuaca, 'kan?
What if we drop the weather fruits when we try? That's dangerous.
Bagaimana jika buah cuaca jatuh saat diuji? Itu bahaya.
Let's test them with small weather fruits. It won't be dangerous then.
Mari uji dengan buah kecil. Itu takkan berbahaya.
You said small weather fruits.
Kau bilang buah cuaca kecil.
You didn't have to bring so many, did you?
Kau tak perlu bawa sebanyak ini.
It's fine.
Tak apa-apa.
A bigger load can test
Beban yang lebih besar
if the wings are capable of delivering larger weather fruits.
bisa uji apa sayapnya mampu bawa buah lebih besar.
Fine then.
Baiklah.
It works!
Berhasil!
Look.
Lihat.
The director's remote control wings are wobbling in the sky.
Sayap kendali jarak jauh Direktur tak stabil.
The remote control wings are crashing.
Sayapnya mau jatuh.
Don't worry. Let me adjust them.
Jangan khawatir. Biar kuatur.
You adjusted too much. Go right...
Penyesuaiannya terlalu banyak. Ke kanan...
Okay... Go left... Why is it going up?
Bagus... Ke kiri... Kenapa tak naik?
-Oh, no! It's crashing into a wall! -Oh, no! It's falling! It's crashing...
- Tidak! Menabrak dinding! - Tidak! Jatuh! Akan tabrak...
After working hard all morning, it's my happy lunchtime again.
Setelah kerja keras sepanjang pagi, ini sudah saat makan siang.
Waiter, please give me a lunch set.
Pramusaji, satu set makan siang.
Enjoy your meal.
Selamat makan.
The plump rice grains, the crunchy and fresh vegetables,
Biji padi montok, sayuran renyah dan segar,
with a bit of refreshing carrot,
dengan wortel segar,
the rich aroma with a slightly burned smell...
aroma lezat dengan sedikit bau hangus...
Burned?
Hangus?
What's going on?
Ada apa?
Who threw firecrackers in the canteen?
Siapa yang lempar petasan di kantin? Kemarilah!
-Sorry.
- Maaf.
Hope, why did you throw firecrackers?
Kenapa kau melempar petasan?
Boss, we didn't throw firecrackers.
Bos, kami tak lempar petasan. Kami menguji sayap kendali jarak jauh.
Hope, your idea is great.
Hope, idemu memang hebat.
But I told you not to test the remote control wings anymore.
Tapi sudah kubilang jangan ada pengujian lagi.
Look at what you've done to the canteen.
Lihat akibatnya terhadap kantin.
Boss, I know I was wrong.
Aku tahu aku salah.
I screwed up again.
Aku mengacau lagi.
You just wanted to help out.
Kau hanya mau membantu.
It's hard to operate the remote control wings properly.
Sulit mengoperasikan sayap kendali dengan baik.
Right! Since manual control is prone to error,
Benar! Karena kontrol manual rentan terhadap salah,
we can control it with the computer instead.
kita bisa kendalikan dengan komputer.
With the computer?
Komputer?
We can write a computer program to control the wings.
Kita bisa buat program komputer untuk mengendalikan sayap.
There won't be any error then.
Takkan ada eror lagi.
Are you writing a computer program?
Kau membuat program komputer?
Yes, we want to write a program to control the wings.
Ya, kami mau buat program untuk mengendalikan sayap,
But it's so hard to write a computer program.
tapi sulit buat program komputer.
Oh, it's so simple.
Itu cukup mudah.
You know how to write one?
Kau bisa membuatnya?
What's so surprising about that?
Kenapa kalian terkejut?
Other than programing, I know karate, playing the piano, surfing, and DJ-ing.
Selain memprogram, aku bisa karate, main piano, berselancar, dan disjoki.
Can you help us then?
Kau bisa membantu kami?
Of course... not.
Tentu... tidak.
Why not?
Kenapa tidak?
What if an accident happens again?
Bagaimana jika ada kecelakaan lagi?
Paddi, let's continue.
Paddi, mari kita lanjutkan.
I heard you catch a cold. I brought you soup.
Kudengar kau sakit flu. Ini kubawakan sup.
-I hope you'll get better soon. -Thank you so much, Director.
- Semoga lekas sembuh. - Terima kasih, Direktur.
That's wrong. You should press this button.
Itu salah. Seharusnya tekan tombol ini.
Let me handle it.
Biar kuurus.
It's done.
Selesai.
Now, the remote control wings can be controlled electronically.
Kini, sayap kendali jarak jauh bisa dikontrol secara elektronis.
-Thank you! -It's fine... It's just a small matter.
- Terima kasih! - Tak apa. Ini masalah kecil.
Really?
Sungguh?
Can you help with these too?
Bisa bantu dengan ini juga?
Weslie, I have great news.
Weslie, aku punya kabar baik.
Hold on with that.
Tahan dulu.
I am being attacked by Wolffy right now.
Aku sedang diserang Wolffy.
Weslie, surrender!
Weslie, menyerahlah!
Wolffy caught up again.
Wolffy mengejarku lagi.
I need to find a way to get rid of him.
Cari cara untuk mengusirnya.
Did I lose Wolffy yet?
Apa aku kehilangan Wolffy?
I heard that you are looking for me.
Kudengar kau mencariku.
See what I have in store for you!
Lihat apa yang sudah kusiapkan.
Oh, no!
Tidak!
Magic Train! Transform!
Kereta Ajaib! Berubah!
What's going on?
Apa itu?
I am slowed down again by Weslie.
Aku diperlambat lagi oleh Weslie.
I have no time to deal with you.
Aku tak punya waktu berurusan denganmu.
You want to run away? Not so fast.
Kau mau lari? Tidak secepat itu.
Oh, no! The weather fruits fell.
Tidak! Buah cuacanya jatuh.
Weslie!
Weslie!
You're not getting away!
Kau takkan bisa lari!
I will be back!
Aku akan kembali!
The weather fruits are close to the ground.
Buah cuaca sudah dekat tanah.
-What's going on? -Weslie!
- Apa yang terjadi? - Weslie!
Paddi!
Paddi!
Hurry! Hurry, everyone!
Cepat! Cepat, Semua!
There're still so many fruits that haven't been delivered. What to do?
Masih banyak buah yang belum diantarkan. Harus bagaimana?
Aren't those Hope's remote control wings?
Bukankah itu sayap kendali jarak jauh Hope?
Oh, no! One pair of wings blew up the canteen last time.
Tidak! Sepasang sayap meledakkan kantin terakhir kali.
There are so many pairs this time.
Kini ada banyak sekali sayap.
Looks like Weather City will be destroyed under my watch.
Tampaknya Kota Cuaca akan hancur di bawah pengawasanku.
-Boss... -What's going on?
- Bos... - Ada apa?
Did the canteen blow up again?
Apa kantinnya hancur lagi?
No, the weather fruits are heading towards their designated destinations.
Buah-buahan cuaca pergi menuju tujuan mereka.
What's going on?
Ada apa ini?
The new generation wings are now controlled by computer.
Sayap generasi baru dikendalikan oleh komputer.
We can avoid errors caused by manual control.
Bisa kurangi unsur kesalahan manual.
I've also created a mobile app.
Aku juga membuat aplikasi seluler.
Customers who want to buy weather fruits
Pelanggan bisa beli buah cuaca lewat aplikasi
Hope, thanks to your wings,
Hope, berkat sayapmu,
the crisis of our factory is resolved.
krisis pabrik sudah teratasi.
I didn't do it alone. Everyone helped.
Aku tak bertindak sendirian. Semua membantu.
TO BE CONTINUED 2780 DAYS FROM SETTING SAIL
BERSAMBUNG 2.780 HARI SEBELUM PULANG